[ Background sounds ]
>> I've been asked to help
a team evaluate students
who are hard of hearing and deaf
to see they had vision loss.
And because one of the syndromes
that people maybe deaf or hard
of hearing due to Usher's
Syndrome comes with vision loss.
My colleagues and I went
to the school and we began
to evaluate the students.
And it became clear that one
student especially was having
visual difficulties.
When we did the vision
evaluation, basically we found
that this is where she saw.
This little area here and it
was pretty disturbing to find
out that she had actually been
kicked out of another school
because her friends
had kind of labeled her
and teachers had labeled
her of being paranoid
and accusing others and lying.
And what had happened
was in gym class,
she thought that people were
deliberately throwing balls
directly at her.
And she thought that her
friends were sneaking up on her
to deliberately surprise
and bother her.
And what nobody knew, sadly,
was that from her point
of view that's really
what happened.
And so it's really important
to be sure when we're looking
at some of the reasons why
children may behave a certain
way or have certain
social difficulties.
Let's look at the sensory
perspective of it to see
if there is something
else that might be going
on that would explain
it and then
that we can do something about.