♪♪
[piano music]
I'll be so frustrated,
it's like I was trying
to say out or...
like trying to know
what is going around you
I don't see how I'm gonna
interact with my family
and I can't see them
and I can't hear them.
Like you couldn't play sports
or hang out with your friends.
My life will change
like a hundred percent.
♪♪
It's very complex
and every deaf-blind
person, child,
is totally different
but deaf-blindness is huge,
it's huge.
Deaf-blindness
is seeing and hearing
in a different way.
(woman)
There is so much inside
that you may not know is there
until you start
building a bond of trust
you're going to learn so much
about that child
some of these kids and adults
are the funniest people
that I had ever met.
(man)
The students who, who...
I didn't know
what to make of
when I first met them
other than,
they seem interesting
and I wanted to get
to know them
but as I begun
to learn about
calendar systems
and communication systems,
I realize that
the learning potential,
the ceiling for these students
was way higher than I,
than I ever realized.
¡Oh my gosh!, this stuff
works really well,
really well,
and it's so much fun.
♪♪