(male decriber)
A young deaf-blind man
and his SSP
approach to a large metal sphere
mounted to a red and black
brick plaza.
A building and trees are visible
in the background
and also in the reflection
of the sphere's near-surface.
They begin discussing
the interactive sculpture
which is located
on the college campus.
The man has his
right hand extended
feeling the surface
of the sphere
As a third man wanders up
to the sculpture,
the SSP says to the first man:
there's a plunger
when you press it,
it rings a bell.
He then rings the bell
and asks him if he is surprised
by its reverberation.
They continue to discuss
the installation
using tactile communication,
the specifics
of the conversation
is unclear.
Two ladies approach the sphere.
One loudly slaps it
with the palm of her hand
as she walks around it.
The plunger
located about waist high
for an adult
is being pressed repeatedly
continually ringing the bell.
The SSP describes
the sound of the bell
while the young man
feels for the vibrations.
After ringing the bell
several times,
he reaches up
trying to determine
where the top of the sphere is.
He asks if it's possible
to climb on top
of the sculpture.
The SSP replies
that its over six foot tall.
He wonders how tall the SSP is,
and receives the answer:
six foot three inches.
He then asks what it is made up
and the SSP replies with:
metal or possibly another alloy.
There's an identical plunger
on the opposite side
he then goes on to explain
that this sculpture
is reflective
and that he can see himself
in it.
As the man presses
the plunger again,
a lady's laugh is heard.
They continue talking about
the installation.
The SSP asks the man
what he thinks
about the sculpture
but his response cannot be seen.
Using his right hand
he tries to determine
the shape and dimensions
of the sculpture.
He asks the SSP
if it's a globe.
The SSP invites him
to walk around the sculpture.
A camera flash can be seen
in the reflective surface
of the sphere.
With his right hand patting
the surface of the globe
he follows the SSP slowly around
to the opposite side
where a second plunger is found.
The young man presses
the plunger
and is told by the SSP
that additional force
creates a lot of ring.
He peers closely
at this reflection
before tapping the sphere
with his hand.
Other people who are also
examining the sculpture
are visible in the background.
The young man continues
to tap the sphere
and peer closely
into it's reflective surface.
The man continue to talk,
the conversation
at this point is unclear.
The SSP then begins to describe
the shape and size
of the plunger.
He explains that the plunger
is circular
and it's about the size
of a man hand.
It is connected
to a thin metal rod
running into the middle
of the sphere.
The man uses his foot to feel
for the base of the sculpture.
He asks if it is possible
to push on the sphere
in cause it to rollaway.
The SSP jokingly replies
that if he wishes
to take the risk,
he can try.
He then shows the man
that if you push on it,
it will not move.
Do you want to try to push it?
look, I'm pushing it.
I can't do it,
it's mounted to something,
it's attached.
Well, I wonder if I could sit
on the top?
Would you like me
to lift you up there?
I could lift you up
if you want.
Will it break?
No, and I don't think
I could really
lift you up there
But you can try to touch
the top if you jump.
Look, this is as far
as I can touch.
You know,
I can't touch the top.
He tries to jump
to the top again.
I can lift you up.
Uh, but what if I fall?
Well that's true,
it's too tall.
The video ends abruptly.
Closed caption by Dicapta.
www.dicapta.com